João de Maredo Borges

Porto, Portugal



hello@jbbmb.com



linkedin.com/in/jbbmb



Summary

Everyone around João knew he was meant to work with technology since 1997, the year he was born. After high school, he started his Bachelor's in Computer Sciences, got involved in numerous freelance projects and began experimenting with different industry roles. Over the years, he worked with insightful teams using a range of tools, such as Jira, and technologies, like Java. Recently, he grew a special attention to detail for Quality Control and Agile Processes, fell in love with User Experience and wants to learn more about SwiftUI and modern FrontEnd frameworks. One thing to remember about him is that he can make a mean gin and tonic.

Experience

Senior System & Network Administrator

BOLD by Devoteam

Jan 2022 - Present (1 month +)

With heavy focus on Atlassian's Jira management, João's current aim is to help BOLD continuously deliver a set of specialized organizational capabilities to its customers and partners, enabling value in the form of cloud services.

System Administrator

Plásticos Bueso II

Jun 2019 - Present (2 years 8 months +)

From online presence, to order processing and security updates, João helps to maintain all of the IT infrastructure required to run his family's plastics injection business.

Quality Assurance Analyst

FOURSOURCE

Apr 2021 - Nov 2021 (8 months)

With the same intent, João took on the responsibility of being QA's first line of defense. His role was to transform expected behavioral requirements into fully decomposed, materialized and testable acceptance criteria, that go on to be developed in Go+Angular.

Junior Product Manager

FOURSOURCE

Sep 2020 - Apr 2021 (8 months)

Bridging the gap between stakeholders' expectations and team commitment, João's purpose at FOURSOURCE was quite simple: to continue delivering an engaging, tailored experience inside the largest B2B sourcing platform for apparel and textiles.

Junior C# Full Stack Developer

CPCIT4ALL

Mar 2019 - Jun 2019 (4 months)

João's mission at this HR-focused company was to help during a critical transition to newer, web-based technologies. He was tasked with refining and re-implementing existing components, using mostly ASP.NET and pure JavaScript, to be re-used at a later stage.

Junior Java Full Stack Developer

Celfocus

Apr 2018 - Jul 2018 (4 months)

This challenge involved refactoring a Java Spring-based corporate social network into a platform that could retain acquired skills by staff and match them to a new project, given its technical requirements.

Education

Instituto Superior de Engenharia do Porto

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Sciences 2015 - Present

Externato Ribadouro

High School Diploma, Sciences and Technology 2012 - 2015

Licenses & Certifications

Certificate of C2 Proficiency in English - Cambridge Assessment English
A4565478

Skills

Agile & Waterfall Methodologies • Software Quality Assurance • Unified Modeling Language (UML) Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • JavaScript • Java • C# • ASP.NET MVC • Git • macOS

Honors & Awards

1st ever "Cherry Pick Porto" Staff - Núcleo de Estudantes de Informática do ISEP Jun 2016